

(985) 696-4781

chadlefort@gmail.com
github.com/ChadLefort
chadlefort.com

I've always had a strong passion for the web. Shortly after I was given my first computer, I grew interested in web development. I take pride in writing clean, maintainable, and efficient code and have always enjoyed the feeling of accomplishment when programming. I not only take pride in my own work, but genuinely care that the team I'm a part of succeeds in delivering great products that offer an excellent user experience. I'm also constantly furthering my skills by learning new patterns, libraries, and frameworks to keep up with the ever changing demand the web has.

# **Job Experience**

### Veriforce

**Senior Frontend Engineer** 

July 2017 - Present

Architecting applications in React, Redux, TypeScript, and Material-UI and writing unit tests with Jest and React Testing Library for a contractor management platform.

Lead a team of two developers that met client deadlines for major revenue growing projects.

Mentor teammates by having pair programming sessions and providing feedback on code reviews daily.

Advocate for UI and code consistency throughout the application by creating patterns for other teammates to follow.

Set up a monorepo using Lerna for over a dozen React applications and NPM packages saving hours from weekly manual deployments.

Quarterly manage dependency upgrades that may fix underlying bugs and allow developers to use new features.

Proposed TypeScript and migrated existing React applications to it to reduce bugs and provide a better developer experience.

#### Netchex

**Full Stack Software Developer** 

November 2014 - July 2017

Worked in an agile environment on an application that specialized in payroll, benefits, and human resources.

Led a team of three developers on a rewrite of the benefits module.

Developed applications using domain driven design with C# for REST APIs and created single page applications using AngularJS, TypeScript, and Bootstrap.

### **Edison Chouest Offshore**

**PLC Programmer** 

December 2013 - November 2014

Implemented automation systems on several vessels using ladder logic and GE PLCs.

Modified logic using GE Proficy and created custom interfaces for vessels using GE Cimplicity.

### **SCPDC**

#### Software Developer Intern

February 2013 - November 2013

Developed client sites using WordPress, Bootstrap, PHP, and jQuery and modified custom reports using MS SQL Server.

### Skills

















## Education

# **Nicholls State University**

Bachelor of Science (B.S.)

August 2009 - December 2013



Majored in Computer Information Systems

GPA: 3.6

#### **Awards**

Consistently been awarded the President's List award since the Fall 2010 semester. The President's List award requires a student to maintain a scholastic GPA of 3.5 or higher.

### **Organizations**

Member of Beta Gamma Sigma. It is the highest recognition a business student anywhere in the world can receive in a business program accredited by AACSB International.

Member of Upsilon Pi Epsilon. It is the first and only existing international honor society in the Computing and Information disciplines.